ZACCHEAUS AMENYA

LinkedIn: Zaccheaus Amenya Email: zamenya98@gmail.com Website: https://bit.ly/3vlwMJh Contact: 0700-322-829

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A passionate software developer with experience in the development and maintenance of applications. Excels in every stage of software development life cycle, including design creation, coding, debugging, testing, and maintenance. Expert in devising innovative and tailored solutions to assist businesses in achieving their goals in a variety of industries. Advanced skills and knowledge of leading programming tools with a strong background in mathematics, algorithms, and data-processing logic.

CAREER HISTORY

STL Horizon

Dec 2021 - to Date

Developer

- Write functional, unit, and integration tests for application quality assurance.
- Developing Flutter apps using GetX framework.
- Identify the current user's need and pain points from the available system, develop the solution and release it.
- Coordinate with champion users to get the feedback on new design of the solution and
- Explore the different Tech Stack for Cross platform development.

Mradi Kenya

Oct 2021 -Dec 2021

Ruby on Rails developer(Remote Internship)

- Write functional, unit, and integration tests for application quality assurance.
- Performed extensive tests to ensure top app performance.
- Employed Windows 10 Mobile emulators in testing protocol.
- Documented test results and delivered them to the application development team.
- Identifying bottlenecks and bugs, and devising solutions .

Clook Technologies

July 2021 -Nov 2021

Junior Software Developer

- Modified existing software to detect and correct errors, improve performance, and upgrade interfaces.
- Prepared reports on specifications and activities for each project.
- Collaborated well with other team members to determine the best design specifications and details.
- Designed web applications and maintained content for multiple. NET-based systems.

Network Support Engineer

- Designed, configured, and installed Data Center Network Devices to support 500+ users, including running cables, ports, routers, switches, Load Balancers, and VPNs
- Effectively resolved routing issues within multiple contexts of the Sophos firewall
- Detected 20+ network vulnerabilities by testing infrastructure security and tracking potential threats to the network
- Created 12 secure networks, both local and wide-area.
- All computer hardware and accessories are kept in perfect shape, ensuring smooth operations.

Safaricom PLC - Nairobi, Kenya. Assistant Agile Couch

March 2021 - June 2021

All organization members can drive and support adopting an agile mindset, techniques, and culture by all organization members according to both best practices and Safaricom digital strategy.

- Coached and supported a team of 13 in the adoption of the Agile/Scrum process.
- Evaluated and mentored existing Scrum teams.
- Developed and delivered training workshops for product owners, teams, and stakeholders.

Contact: 0700-322-829 Email: <u>zamenya98@gmail.com</u>

- Promoted application of Agile principles and values and their application through popular methodologies and frameworks (Scrum.) at the team and management levels.
- Drove continuous improvement of IT Project Delivery processes including Agile/Scrum methods.

Software Tester

Reviewing, analyzing, and Executing software requirements and test results on database impacts, errors or bugs, and usability.

- Delivered thorough QA testing reports that determined product quality and release readiness.
- Successfully rolled out changes on okoa Journey enhancement Regression.
- Successfully Rolled out a regression, including the Service fee on the okoa jahazi menu and Tunukiwa customer journey.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Good understanding of Java, Kotlin, Flutter, PHP(Laravel), with MySQL and SpringBoot.
- Software Testing Skills, Application Security, problem-solving and algorithmic skills.
- Good understanding of Azure, Jira, Git tools, Android SDK, REST APIs.
- Experience with firewalls, Internet VPN's remote implementation, and troubleshooting.
- Staying abreast of new technologies.
- Good communication and reporting and documentation skills.
- Intensive knowledge in Windows, Unix/Linux Operating Systems.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

BSc. Information Technology - Masinde Muliro University of Science and Technology. **Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education** - Kanyawanga High School.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

Scrum Master Certification Training - Master of Project Academy
Agile with Atlassian Jira - Atlassian
Scrum Fundamentals Certified - SCRUMstudy
Azure DevOps and AWS DevOps - Udemy
Internet of Things Certified - Motorola Solutions
May 3, 2021
April 29, 2021
April 6, 2021
December 8, 2020
February 28, 2020

April 15, 2020

Google analytics - Google Analytics Academy

REFERENCES

Mr. Wesley Mogaka CVM Capabilities Manager, Safaricom ltd

Tel: 0726775143

Email:wmmogaka@safaricom.co.ke

Mr. Samuel Odiwuor VAS Engineer, Safaricom PLC

Tel: 0700865187

Email: sodiwor@safaricom.co.ke

Dr. Daniel Otanga PhD

Dean, School of Computing and Informatics, Masinde Muliro University

Tel: 0722234554

Email: otanga@mmust.ac.ke

Contact: 0700-322-829 Email: <u>zamenya98@gmail.com</u>